Vishal Shinde

Phone: 9518516315 / 8087124688 Email: <u>vsvshinde15@gmail.com</u>

Github: Github/Vishal Shinde LinkedIn: Linkedin/Vishal

Summary

A fast learner, self driven and highly motivated team player, with an ability to stay organized and focused in fast-paced multitasking environments with a keen eye for details.

With 6 + years of experience under the belt, Javascript is the programming language I've spent most of my time working with features ranging from Async/Await, Promises, Regular expressions, Objects, Cookies and Client side Storage APIs.

Engineering multiple websites that serve millions of users daily from different parts of the world. Leading the development with a team of 6, writing multiple types of pages along with mentoring and supervising juniors.

Administering javascript code standards and conventions to maintain the best code quality in the market all the while minding the deadlines.

Skills

Programming:: JavaScript, Node.Js

Web-Frontend:: ReactJs, Redux, NextJs, Webpack, Jquery, HTML5, CSS, SCSS/SASS, Flexbox

Web-Backend:: Express with Node.JS,

Database :: MySQL, MongoDB

Tools:: JIRA, Github, Bitbucket (CI/CD), SVN, Google lighthouse, NPM, Heroku

Work Experience

Zscaler (June 2020 – Current)

Designation :: Software Engineer - II

Project :: Cloud security posture management

Technology:: ReactJS, Redux, NodeJs, Webpack module federation, Microsoft Azure

Description:: Working on different modules of the software i.e. User management, Asset Inventory, User authentication using JWT token and session management. Working on page

speed optimization using google lighthouse. Working on Content security policy related issues.

CodeAstu Technologies Private Limited

(September 2019 - June 2020)

Designation:: Front-end Engineer

Project :: Prescription Coupon & Discount Cards Website

Technology :: ReactJS, Redux, Nodejs, Webpack, Underscore, Express

Description:: Spearheaded the development of multiple Modules from ground up including the Drug Basket, Prescription, User account & Signup / Login. Implemented Pharmacy search page using google maps API. Implemented Node BFF to secure API calls and improve API response time. Worked on improving page speed performance using google lighthouse.

Contributed in complete website translation from english to spanish using React-i18next.

MangoApps

(March 2018 - August 2019)

Designation :: Front-end Engineer **Duration ::** March 2018 – August 2019

Project :: Team Collaboration & Employee Engagement Software

Technology:: ReactJS, Redux, Webpack, Sass, Underscore

Description :: Worked on different modules of the software i.e. Advanced search, Embed Post and Template module. Developed reusable and easy to integrate search and filter functionality from scratch. Worked to reduce the build size by removing optimizing the javascript code & and writing reusable components.

Webonise Lab

(August 2016 – March 2018)

Designation :: Front-end Engineer

Duration :: August 2016 – March 2018

Project :: Aircraft Ecommerce Website

Technology :: ReactJS, Redux, Web pack, Sass, Underscore

Description:: Developed a responsive and cross browser compliant website for one of the largest international brokerage and aircraft consulting firms.

Built user friendly and highly responsive Aircraft search and filter module with React.

Education

Pune Institute of Computer Technology, Pune - B.E.(Information Technology)(2012-2016)

Yeshwant College, Nanded - (HSC) (2012)

Pratibha Niketan High School, Nanded - (SSC) (2010)